lemonade.com 2008-12-17

# lemonade :: Privacy Policy

Effective Date: August 28, 2007This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) is designed to explain: (i) how Lemonade, Inc. (along with its affiliates from time to time, hereafter, individually and collectively, “we”, “us” or “Lemonade”) collects, uses and shares information, (ii) what type(s) of information we collect; (iii) with whom the information may be shared; (iv) what choices are available to you regarding our collection, use, and sharing of the information; (v) how you can access, edit and/or delete certain information; (vi) the kind of security procedures in place to protect personal information that is under our control; and (vii) covers all of our Services.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Lemonade does not own or control, or to people that Lemonade does not employ or manage. 

Where more detailed information is needed to explain our privacy practices, we may post separate privacy notices to describe how particular services collect, use and share information; such privacy notices are incorporated herein by this reference. We hope this will help you make an informed decision about sharing information with us.

By accessing or using the Services, you agree to this Privacy Policy. This is our entire and exclusive privacy policy and it supersedes any earlier version(s). This Privacy Policy is part of our [Terms of Service](http://www.lemonade.com/about/legal/terms-of-service/) (“Terms of Service” or “TOS”), including any Additional Terms (as such term is defined therein). Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, all capitalized terms defined in said [Terms of Service](http://www.lemonade.com/about/legal/terms-of-service/) or Additional Terms shall have the meanings ascribed to such terms therein.

There are many aspects of our Services that can be enjoyed as a visitor, but you need to register in order to take advantage of certain Services.

Information Collection and UseWe collect personally identifiably information (“PII”) and non-personally identifiable information (“Non-PII”, together with PII, collectively, “Information”) for the following purposes: 

• Providing our products and Services,   
• provide reports,   
• make payments,  
• customize the content and advertising you see,   
• fulfill your requests for our products and Services,   
• for purposes of contacting or notifying you,  
• visitor traffic patterns,  
• to pre-fill fields,  
• auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our Services,  
• ensuring the technical functioning and optimization of our network, and  
• developing new Services.

By knowing about you, we can deliver more helpful information, programs and tools, and offer you the most relevant Services.

Types of Personally Identifiable Information We Collect and From Whom

You may be asked to provide PII in certain fields on the Services. We collect PII when you voluntarily provide it to us or when you authorize us to collect it on your behalf.

The type(s) of PII we collect from you depends on how you utilize the Services. Our Services allow for the following types of users: Operators, Registered Visitors, Non-registered Visitors and LS Visitors (individually and collectively, “user”, “you” or “your”). A description of all such users and the type(s) of PII we collect from each of them, if any, are set forth below.

(i) “Operator(s)” are persons that have registered with us to design, create, build, publish, post, operate and update a Lemonade Stand. We may collect all or any of the following PII from Operators:

o First and last name   
o Company, home, postal or other physical address  
o Other contact information, including your telephone number, fax number, email address, other online contact information, such as an instant messaging user identifier or a screen name that reveals an individual’s email address, a persistent identifier, such as a customer number held in a cookie or processor serial number, that is combined with other available data that identifies an individual, account information (user name and password), and any other information from or about an individual that is combined with any of the above  
o Date of Birth  
o Gender  
o Pay Pal, bank or other financial account information  
o Personal description and photograph in your Profile  
o Profile information provided to us from Merchants and Partners  
o Social security and drivers license number(s)  
o Any other Information needed to provide you with a Service 

(ii) “Registered Visitors” are users of the Services that have registered with us solely to participate in our Public Forums (defined below). We may collect the following PII from Registered Visitors:

o Username  
o E-mail address  
o Password

(iii) “Non-registered Visitor(s)” is anyone that accesses and/or uses our Services, but does not register with us. We do not collect any PII from Non-registered Visitors.

(iv) “LS Visitor(s)” is anyone that accesses or uses a Lemonade Stand, other than the Operator of such Lemonade Stand. We do not collect any PII from LS Visitors.

Examples of scenarios where our Operators and Registered Visitors may provide their PII include, but may not be limited, to:

• Emailing, calling, accessing, using or communicating with Lemonade or the Services   
• Posting a question or comment through the Services   
• Requesting information, data, material or content   
• Registering  
• Setting up accounts  
• Lemonade Stand set up and operation  
• Profile set up and operation  
• Transactions  
• Customer service  
• Technical Support  
• Participating in an online survey   
• Requesting inclusion in an email or other mailing list  
• Invitations  
• Submitting an entry for a contest or other promotions  
• Filling out a questionnaire   
• Logging in to the Services  
• Submitting Content   
• Any other business-related reason

We will allow you to either agree or decline to give your PII via the Internet. We will inform you of the purpose for the collection and we do not intend to share or transfer your PII with/to third parties without your consent, except under the limited conditions described below. If you choose to provide us with your PII, we may communicate with you at the contact information you have provided. When we use third parties to assist us in processing your PII, we require that they comply with our Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

Processing of PII

Lemonade processes PII on our or our Third Party Provider’s servers in the United States of America and in other countries. In some cases, we process PII on a server outside your own country. We may process PII to provide our own Services. In some cases, we may process PII on behalf of and according to the instructions of a third party, such as our Merchants and Partners.

Children Under Age 13

Lemonade does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [info@lemonade.com](mailto:info@lemonade.com).

Children Between the Ages of 13 and 18

We recommend that minors over the age of 13 ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet.

Domain Information Collection 

Lemonade may collect domain information to enable us or our Merchants or Partners to analyze how users use our Services. This data enables us to become more familiar with which people visit our Services, how often they visit, and what parts of the Services they visit and/or interact with most often. Lemonade uses this information to improve its and our Merchants’ and Partners’ Web-based offerings. This information is collected automatically and requires no action on your part. Our Merchants and Partners may use your IP address to determine your approximate geographic location in order to provide you with location-relevant Links, information and advertising.

Use of Cookies and Tracking User Traffic

Some pages on the Services may use “cookies”—small files that the Services place on your hard drive for identification purposes. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID to track the pages visited, but the only PII a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. These files are used for Services registration and customization the next time you visit us.  
Some parts of the Services may also use cookies to track user traffic patterns. Lemonade does this in order to determine the usefulness of our Services information to our users and to see how effective our navigational structure is in helping users reach that information. Please note that cookies cannot read data off of your hard drive. Your Web browser may allow you to be notified when you are receiving a cookie, giving you the choice to accept it or not. If you prefer not to receive cookies while browsing our Services, you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser, by not accepting cookies, some pages may not fully function and you may not be able to access certain information on the Services.

Web Beacons We also use Web beacons, sometimes called single-pixel GIFs, that momentarily direct your browser to a server other than Lemonade’s in a way that may not be apparent to you. Web beacons are used to count users who visited specific pages and determine which emails were opened and/or acted upon when we send HTML-formatted email messages. We do not link any PII to Web beacons. 

Third Party Advertisers and Links to Other WebsitesOur Services include third-party advertising, offers and Links to other websites. We do not provide any personally identifiable customer information to these third-party websites and advertisers, or Internet advertising companies working on their behalf (collectively, starting with “third party websites” “Advertisers”), except as specifically set forth herein or any Additional Terms. 

These Advertisers, sometimes use technology to send (or “serve”) the advertisements or offers that appear on our Services directly to your browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (also known as action tags or single-pixel gifs), and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and offers and to personalize advertising and offer content. We do not have access to or control over cookies or other features that they may use, and the information practices of these Advertisers are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Please contact them directly for more information about their privacy practices. In addition, the Network Advertising Initiative offers useful information about Internet advertising companies (also called “ad networks” or ‘network advertisers”), including information about how to opt-out of their information collection. 

We also display targeted advertising based on personal information about users. Although Lemonade does not provide any personal information to advertisers, advertisers (including ad-serving companies) may assume that users who interact with or click on a targeted advertisement meet the targeting criteria used to display the ad (for example, users in the northwestern United States who like skateboarding).

“Lemonade Stand Information” that may be collected and monitored includes, but is not limited to:

o Lemonade Stand content  
o Lemonade Stand revenue data  
o Lemonade Stand click through and impression data  
o Lemonade Stand launch date(s)  
o Lemonade Stand modification event(s)  
o Lemonade Stand Name(s)  
o Lemonade Stand Internet Location  
o Any other information related to a Lemonade Stand

We may collect, use, share, transfer or provide Lemonade Stand Information for any business purpose whatsoever without your consent.

Information That We Obtain From Third PartiesWe will use third party information, combined with Information you provide to us and Information collected by our and our Third Party Provider’s, Merchant’s and Partner’s systems, to better understand the characteristics of Operators and the visitors to and uses of our Services and to enhance and/or develop new Services. This information will also allow us to tailor content, advertising, Products and offers to your specific interests and needs.

When we associate information that we obtain from third parties with PII that we have collected under this policy, we will treat the acquired information like the information that we collected ourselves. We will not share information we obtain from third parties in personally identifiable form, except under the limited conditions described herein and below. However, we may share aggregated and other non-PII as described in this Privacy Policy. This may include information we obtain from third parties in a form that does not permit you to be identified. We may obtain and use this kind of information from third parties without receiving further permission from you to do so. 

Information Disclosure to Third Parties

We know how important it is to keep the information you have entrusted to us confidential. We will not share PII about you with third parties except to provide you with a product or service you request or under certain circumstances as described herein. In all other cases, we will ask for your permission before we disclose your PII.

Disclosure for Legal Reasons

When we have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of PII is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce applicable Terms of Service or Additional Terms, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of Lemonade, its users, Merchants or Partners or the public as required or permitted by law.

Third PartiesWe provide PII to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies or other trusted businesses or persons for the purpose of processing PII and/or providing the Services on our behalf. We require that these parties agree to process and/or use such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

Contests and SweepstakesLemonade may offer or co-sponsor sweepstakes and contests. Any information submitted by the user for purposes of participation in these promotions, may be shared publicly and with any affiliates of the promotion. This information may be necessary for contacting you with regard to status of the promotion or prizes awarded. All contests and sweepstakes will specifically inform the participants whether their information will be shared. 

Changes in Our Corporate Structure If Lemonade becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will provide notice before PII is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

Aggregated, Non-PII We may share aggregated information about you with third parties. This is Information that is combined with the non-PII of other users and does not allow you to be identified or contacted. Depending on the circumstances, we may or may not charge third parties for this aggregated information. We also may not limit the third parties’ use of the aggregated information.

Accessing and Updating PIIWhen you use our Services, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. Some of our Services have different procedures to access, correct or delete users' personal information. We provide the details for these procedures in the specific FAQs for these services. 

Community Areas

The Services feature community areas such as message boards, blogs, chat rooms and other public forums where people with similar interests can share information or where Registered Visitors and Operators can post questions for others to answer (“Public Areas”). Please remember that any information that you post in Public Areas is, by design, open to the public and is not a private, secure service. You should think carefully before disclosing any PII in any Public Areas. What you have written and or posted may be seen, disclosed to or collected by third parties and may be used by others in ways we are unable to control or predict, including to contact you for unauthorized purposes. As with any public forum on any Web site, this information may also appear in third-party search engines like Google, Yahoo, MSN etc.

Co-BrandingSome products or services may be co-branded and offered in conjunction with another company. If you register for or use such products or services, both Lemonade and the other company may receive the Information collected in conjunction with the co-branded product or services. Please refer to that company's privacy policy to determine how that company may use this Information.

Confidentiality and Security Lemonade has implemented commercially reasonable security measures in order to protect your PII from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. Although we make good faith efforts to store the Information collected by us in a secure operating environment that is not available to the public, we cannot guarantee complete security and we shall not be liable for any unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors that may compromise the security of Information. For any additional information about the security measures we use on certain Services, please feel free to email us at the contact information on the Services.

Notice to All Members If you are unsure whether this privacy policy is in conflict with the applicable local rules where you are located, you should not submit your PII to the Services. Anyone who accesses, uses or interacts with the Services who submits PII does thereby consent to: (i) the international transfer and/or storage of such information to a country which may be deemed to have inadequate data protection and (ii) the collection, using and sharing of such information as provided in this Privacy Policy.

Changes to this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is effective August 28, 2007. Lemonade reserves the right to change, modify or update this Privacy Policy at any time without notice and for any reason. Any substantial changes in the way we use your PII may be posted on the Services. Your access, use or interaction with the Services following the posting of such changes or the updated Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of any such changes. We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy frequently to make sure that you understand how we collect, track, compile, use and share information.  
If you have questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy please email us at the contact information on the Services.
